A Guide to the Warren County (Va.) County Court Judgments, 1836-1904 (bulk 1856-1904)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Warren County (Va.) County Court Judgments, 1836-1904 circa (bulk 1856-1904 circa)
The Library of Virginia
1134348-1134519 circa
13 cu. ft. (13 boxes)
Warren County ( Va.) Circuit Court
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These items came to the Library of Virginia in shipments of court papers from Warren County and Accession Number 37019.
Historical Information
Warren County was named for Joseph Warren, the revolutionary patriot who sent Paul Revere and William Dawes on their famous rides and who was killed at the Battle of Bunker Hill. The county was formed from Frederick and Shenandoah counties in 1836.
Scope and Content
Warren County (Va.) County Court Judgments, 1836-1904 circa (bulk 1856-1904 circa), contain civil cases in which justice was administered on the strictly formulated rules of common law. The majority of cases in this record series relate to matters of debt. There are also a few miscellaneous files in this collection.
Arrangement
Arranged chronological.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Additional Warren County Court Records can be found on microfilm at The Library of Virginia web site. Consult "A Guide to Virginia County and City Records on Microfilm."
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Warren County (Va.)--Circuit Court.
Subjects:
Civil procedure--Virginia--Warren County.; Debt--Virginia--Warren County.; Public Records--Virginia--Warren County.
Geographical Names:
Warren County (Va.)--History.
Genre and Form Terms:
Decisions--Virginia--Warren County.; Judicial records--Virginia--Warren County.; Local government records--Virginia--Warren County.
Contents List
- County Court Judgments, 1859-1869
  Box 1 contains County Court Judgments, 1859-1869.
- County Court Judgments, 1858, 1868-1871
  Box 2 contains County Court Judgments, 1858, 1868-1871.
- County Court Judgments, 1854, 1856-1895
  Box 3 contains County Court Judgments, 1854, 1856-1895.
- County Court Judgments, 1856-1858
  Box 4 contains County Court Judgments, 1856-1858.
- County Court Judgments, 1880-1895
  Box 5 contains County Court Judgments, 1880-1895.
- County Court Judgments, 1836-1839
  Box 6 contains County Court Judgments, 1836-1839.
- County Court Judgments, 1839-1842
  Box 7 contains County Court Judgments, 1839-1842.
- County Court Judgments, 1845-1848
  Box 8 contains County Court Judgments, 1845-1848.
- County Court Judgments, 1849-1853
  Box 9 contains County Court Judgments, 1849-1853.
- County Court Judgments, 1842-1844
  Box 10 contains County Court Judgments, 1842-1844.
- County Court Judgments, 1879-1893
  Box 11 contains County Court Judgments, 1879-1893.
- County Court Judgments, 1881-1899
  Box 12 contains County Court Judgments, 1881-1899.
- County Court Judgments, 1883-1904 circa
  Box 13 contains County Court Judgments and Miscellaneous Files such as commonwealth causes, road and bridge, etc., 1883-1904 circa.